# **Timothy Chow**

Phone: 778 938 9907 Email: tmc21@sfu.ca Portfolio: Coming Soon

#### **ABOUT**

I'm a visual UX designer from Vancouver, BC In my work, I aim to create holistic experiences where I focus on making things meaningful. I believe that looking deeper into details matter because who you are designing for matters.

Currently, I am in my third year studying interaction design at Simon Fraser University.

#### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

anec + dote

Designed the front end an e-commerce platform that offers a selection of printed literature.

February 2018

Utilized atomic design methodology to work in a detailed manner to develop the responsiveness of anec + dote.

Designed a compare feature for Yelp's existing

platform that allows people to compare results rather than loading themselves with information.

Conducted primary, secondary, and evaluative research on Yelp's interface and interactions

Developed prototypes and wireframes to tackle

Designed and prototyped a virtual reality headset for

### **COMPETENCIES**

#### **TECHNICAL DESIGN** Adobe CC User experience Interface design Sketch Interaction design Principle Visual design Flinto Illustration SketchUp HTML, CSS Strategy

#### **RESEARCH WORKING ON**

Personas	JavaScript
Heuristics	Journey frameworks
User testing	Copywriting

Generative research

November – December 2017

### Yelp: Feature Design

November - December 2017

### photogra-VR

materiality and product interactions.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### SIMON FRASER UNIVERSITY

· Pursuing a Bachelor of Arts in Interactive Arts and Technology with a concentration in design.

#### Spring 2018 - Present MINOR

· Pursuing a minor in Print and Digital Publishing.

#### INDUSTRY CONNECT

#### **GRAPHICS AND MEDIA ARTS** 2015

· Stepping stone in my career where I learned technical skills prior to enrolling into SFU.

### Worked with existing branding to produce name tags and event banners for Facebook and their website.

Tasked with laying out and designing pages within the paper, ensuring a high quality product.

Collaborated with section editors in order to convey

Collaborated with the parties involved so that the materials reflect its branding and event information.

### RECOGNITION

#### **ENTREPRENEURSHIP AND INNOVATION**

Placed 1st in an academic entrepreneurship and innovation class with a proposal to mend the relationship between transit and people with non-visible disabilities.

### **Audio Engineer**

Emerging Generations, volunteer

2013 - 2016

### Prepared sound equipment and operated the sound board in order to achieve a sound mix that would

vitalize the spirits of guests.

Collaborated with band in order to make them feel comfortable with how they sound.

Conducted primary and secondary research on

travelling photographers.

the written piece visually.

problems within the interface

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Assistant Production Editor**

The Peak Publications, part-time

# Fall 2017 - Present

## **Graphic Designer**

#### Emerging Generations, volunteer Fall 2017 - Present